NO ENTRY
(禁止入内)
Can you explain to me now?
你现在可以向我解释了吧
Before we begin, could you please ask others to leave?
在此之前 能请您让其他人回避吗
They should have all hidden their breath.
他们应该都已经隐藏气息了
Can you see through things?
难道你能透视吗
I will explain this as well.
我会连同这个问题一起向您解释
Hey, did you guys hear it?
喂 你们听到了吧
-But Master… -Just leave.
-但是 主公… -退下
There's no one else around, can you tell me now?
这样就没有其他人了 你可以说了吧
Okay.
好
You may not believe it when I say this,
说出来您也许不会相信
but I am not from this world.
但我不是这个世界的人
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《尸体如山的死亡游戏》
(Episode 7: The Magician)
(第7集 The Magician -魔术师-)
Good job, Nezu.
话说 你这次干得真不错 根津
Thank you.
多谢了
What's wrong?
怎么了
You mean Polka save Kazuki and the others before you?
你说波尔卡先你一步 救下了华月他们
Can you tell me more?
这件事能和我详细地讲讲吗
I see. Your story does sound unbelievable.
原来如此 你的故事 确实听起来让人难以置信
But seeing something like this, I can only believe it.
但看到这样的东西 我也只能相信了
However,
不过
this also means that
这样一来
the person who cut Polka's throat was you,
也就说明割了波尔卡喉咙的人
young girl.
就是小姑娘你啊
Indeed.
嗯 确实如此
Did you just admit it in front of me?
你居然敢当着我的面承认
Are you mentally prepared to die at my hands?
你是已经做好 被我杀掉的心理准备了吗
Or do you think that I am just an old man who is not worth fearing?
还是说 你觉得 我这个老头子根本不足为惧
Well, it's a bit of both.
这个嘛 应该两者都有
You're a good person, so I'm not afraid.
大叔你是个好人 所以我不害怕
Even if you want to kill me, I think there's a reason for it.
就算你要杀我 我觉得也情有可原
WAIT, DON'T KILL HER, FATHER. Oh, what's this?
(等一下 不要杀她 父亲) 咦 这是什么
Wait a minute, father. Don't kill Whitey.
等一下 父亲 不要杀小白
Are…Are you polka?
你…难道是波尔卡吗
BANG, BANG, BANG
(频频点头)
You just said that Polka's soul is safe and sound.
你刚才说波尔卡的灵魂平安无事
Doesn't that mean his soul is sleeping in his own body?
难道你指的不是 他正在自己的肉体中休眠吗
BANG, BANG, SHARK METRONOME
(频频点头) (鲨鱼节拍器)
And he happened to possess the doll of Berg, the shark of hell?
他竟然偏偏附身到了 地狱鲨鱼伯格的玩偶里
COOL, RIGHT?
(很帅气吧)
That's just a temporary solution.
那个 这只是暂时的处理
I really admire this child.
我真是服了这孩子了
And he seems very happy about it, which is a bit too much.
而且 他本人看起来倒是很开心 这样也太卑鄙了吧
I can't even get angry anymore.
我想生气都气不起来了
But surprisingly, there is someone who thinks I'm a good person.
不过 居然有人会觉得我是个好人
Young girl, you don't have a good eye for judging people.
小姑娘 你看人的眼光不太行啊
Let's continue our topic.
也罢 我们继续刚才的话题吧
You just said that you are the Corpse God, right?
你刚才说 你是“尸神殿”对吧
As long as I find a body for you to possess,
只要找到能够让你附身的身体
Polka can return to his original body, right?
波尔卡就能回到 他原本的身体里 对吧
How about I let you use this?
要不我把这个给你用吧
It's an artificial human.
精密的人造人
There are also similar studies in my hometown,
我的家乡也有这类研究
but this one is really…
不过这个真是…
BANG, BANG, BANG, BANG
(拍 拍 拍 拍)
Why not become a robot since you need to change your body?
你说反正都需要换身体 那不如你自己换成机器人
Even if you were given a robot body, it wouldn't make much sense.
等下 即使给你换上机器人身体 也没什么意义啊
Did you say you want a power drill and flying skills?
你说想要电钻和飞行技能
Why do you want to become a rock drill?
为什么你会想变成凿岩机
Ah, it's not quite appropriate to say that he seems to be doing well.
唉 我也不能说他看起来过得很好
But at least he didn't suffer too much.
但至少他没有受苦就好
Anyway, since someone wants to kill Polka,
总之 既然有人想要波尔卡的性命
it's better for you to continue staying inside him.
还是让你继续留在他体内比较好
-Then… -Don't misunderstand me.
-那就… -你可别误会了
I didn't intend to forgive this young girl,
我并没有要原谅这个小姑娘
but since you saved my grandson and granddaughter, I'll let you go for now.
但是 看在你救了我孙子孙女的份上 今天我就先放过你们了
So,
那么
you deliberately didn't mention the "intermediary" just now.
你刚才刻意没有提到“中介人”
Since you're in Shinjuku, it's probably at "Miss Kuraki's" place, right?
既然你们是在新宿 那大概就是“仓木小姑娘”那里吧
There are several people there who are quite difficult to deal with.
那里有好几个人都挺难对付的
I really don't want to go against them.
我实在是不太想和他们作对
Moreover, I don't want to believe that
而且 我也不愿相信
someone in the family would want to kill Polka.
家庭成员中会有人想杀波尔卡
However,
不过
this is probably my retribution.
这也是我的报应吧
That's it.
事情就是这样
We'll go back after we take a quick look at real Polka's pet.
我们看一眼真波尔卡的宠物就回去
You just said that you revealed the truth. Are you serious?
喂喂 你不会真的坦白真相了吧
Yes, but I only told Mr. Rozan the truth.
嗯 不过我只有和吕算先生说
MY TEXTBOOKS…MY GAME CONSOLE…
(我的教科书…我的游戏机…) 你觉得没问题就行吧
I have been allowed to temporarily stay in Shinjuku.
我暂且已经被允许住在新宿了
Um…
那个
I know I'm not qualified to say sorry to you anymore at this point.
事到如今 我知道自己 没有资格向你说对不起了
But I still want to say, I'm sorry.
但我还是要说 对不起
And thank you.
还有 谢谢你
NOT AT ALL
(不用客气)
It's surprising to see
真少见啊
a soul that can be so open-hearted towards the person who killed them.
对杀了自己的人还能如此敞开心扉 像这样的灵魂
It's the first time I've seen it since then.
我自那之后还是第一次见
Wait, Sis Misaki.
等一下 美咲姐姐
Thank you for saving us.
谢谢你 救了我们
We were extremely scared just now…
刚刚我们害怕极了…
It's okay, it's okay.
没关系 没关系
A child unafraid of such scenes would have died.
看到那种场面还不害怕的孩子 怕是早就丢掉性命了吧
Sis Misaki, have you learned martial arts?
美咲姐姐 你学过格斗吗
This is a secret.
这是秘密
Um…Uncle Polka.
那个 波尔卡叔叔
Thank you very much.
非常谢谢您
Thank you.
谢谢
You shouldn't thank me
你们不应该向我道谢
because it wasn't me who saved you just now.
因为刚才救了你们的不是我
It was a diviner from Shinjuku called Corpse God
而是新宿的一个 叫“尸神殿”的占卜师
and your guardian spirit.
还有你们的守护灵
I can't see that guardian spirit, but what are you planning to do?
我是看不见那个守护灵啦 不过你打算怎么做
Do you want to make a contract with that guardian spirit?
你要和那个守护灵签订契约吗
Maybe one day.
有朝一日吧
But not now.
不过 现在就算了
Now is not the right time.
现在还不是时候
Just now, the sub-bureau received news
刚才分局传来消息
that the real Firestarter has appeared.
据说真正的“赴火之虫”出现了
What a coincidence.
哎呀 这还真是凑巧
How about the damage?
损伤情况如何
A police car was burned with an arsonist who was being transported inside.
一辆警车被烧 里面还坐着一个押送中的纵火犯
It seems that the bug just burned its own imitator.
看来那只虫子 只是烧掉了自己的仿冒者而已
Compared to those,
比起那些
I'm more interested in the bones you just mentioned.
我对你们刚提到的“骨头”更感兴趣
If possible, could you show me the video again?
可以的话 能让我再看一次视频吗
Then I'm afraid you'll have to exchange it with the intelligence you know.
那你恐怕 得用自己知道的情报来换了
Is that so? Then it's a pity.
是吗 那还真是遗憾
Well, I'll go explore it myself then.
那么 我就自己去一探究竟吧
Please use this.
请用这个
You really thought it through.
你想得真周到啊
I have learned from the lessons I had at the club before.
我吸取了之前在俱乐部的教训
No way!
不会吧 喂
This guy really exceeded my expectations.
这家伙实在是出乎我的意料
Phantom Solitaire!
怪人雪天鸦
So, let's start the comeback performance of Tena Sorimura.
那么 接下来就开始 我雪车村天鸦的回归演出吧
If there are no audience,
要是没有观众的话
I can only cry alone under the moon.
我就只能独自一人在月下流泪了
IT'S JUST WHITE ON THE APPEARANCE… This is Whitey.
(外表是白色而已…) 这是小白哦
It's really big and adorable.
真大真可爱啊
Real Polka is truly an extraordinary person.
真波尔卡还真是个了不得的大人物
TENA SORIMURA Phantom Solitaire.
(雪车村天鸦) 怪人雪天鸦
EMERGENCY MEETING He escaped from the Tokyo Detention Center
(紧急会议) 今天下午5点30分左右
around 5:30 p.m. today.
他从东京拘留所逃跑了
Excuse me, Team Leader and Mr. Arase,
请问 系长和荒濑先生
didn't you go to interrogate Phantom Solitaire?
你们不是去审问怪人雪天鸦了吗
Yes! He disappeared when I and Arase were interrogating him!
是啊 他就是 在我和荒濑审他的时候消失的
I thought someone was playing a prank on us.
我还以为是有人故意在整我们呢
HEHEHE What is this? It's too funny.
(呵呵呵…) 这算什么 也太好笑了
You can still laugh!
你们还笑得出来
For us, this is not something to be laughed about?
对我们来说 这可不是能说笑的
That guy's first crime was three years ago.
那家伙最初的案子是在三年前
He stole a painting from the art museum and placed it in front of Shinjuku Alta.
他把美术馆的画偷走 然后放在了新宿ALTA的前面
It is said that his motive for doing so was
据说他这么做的动机是想给新宿的
to provide material for online broadcasters.
YouTuber们提供点子
He then made the Tokyo Metropolitan Government Building disappear.
在此之后 他犯的案子是 东京都厅消失事件
He painted the sky and buildings on the outer wall of the building in one night,
他一夜之间 在都厅的外墙上画了天空和大楼
creating an optical illusion that made it appear as if the building had disappeared.
让人乍一看误以为都厅消失了
This was a trick that utilized visual deception.
这是一种利用视觉错觉的戏法
There are many other crimes that he is suspected of committing,
其他还有许多疑似他犯下的罪行
some of which even involve murder.
其中有的甚至还涉及到谋杀
However, there is not enough evidence for this part yet.
不过这部分还没有足够的证据
Among these cases, there is one that made him famous all over the world,
在这些案件中 还有一件使他名扬天下的案子
that is the kidnapping of the Prime Minister.
那就是首相被绑事件
That's right.
没错
It's our Prime Minister Yumenosuke.
就是我们的首相 颈城互梦之助
One day, he was suddenly covered by a black cloth from head to toe.
有一天他突然被一块黑布从头上罩住
The bodyguards quickly removed the cloth,
当时保镖急忙把黑布取下来
but the Prime Minister miraculously disappeared.
但首相却奇迹般地消失了
Dear all, I am a happy offender.
诸位 我是个愉快犯
Therefore, I do not have a specific political stance.
所以我并无任何特定的政治立场
And today, I will prove this point.
我今天就为各位证明这一点
So, in order to show his impartiality, he kidnapped all the leaders
于是 为了表达自己的一视同仁 他就在一天之内
of opposition parties within one day.
把所有的在野党党首全绑架了
NEWS: PRIME MINISTER KIDNAPPING INCIDENT The prime minister was released in the evening of that day.
(快讯 首相被绑事件) 当天傍晚首相就被释放
THE PRIME MINISTER SAID "IT'S REALLY INTERESTING" According to his description, he seemed to have
(首相说“真是有趣”) 他说一回过神来
come back to his senses and found himself reading "Bat killer" in a comic cafe.
就发现自己正在漫画咖啡馆 看《蝙蝠杀手》
He even commented, "It's really interesting."
而且他还评价说“真是有趣”
It's unclear if he meant being kidnapped or the comic.
至于他指的是被绑的经历 还是漫画的内容就无从得知了
THIS IS TOO FUNNY. Even if we try to block the news,
(这也太好笑了) 这下就算再怎么封锁消息
Japan's police system has become a laughingstock around the world.
日本的警备体制 也已沦为全世界的笑柄了
Afterwards, that guy came to the police station and turned himself in.
后来那个家伙就来警局自首了
That guy was definitely not a normal person.
那家伙果然不是正常人
What brings you here?
什么风把你给吹来了
There is no reaction, which I can't accept.
一点反应也没有 这让我无法接受啊
What? The whole society is discussing you now.
啥 现在整个社会都在讨论你耶
I'm not talking about this.
我说的不是这个
I mean,
我是说
I want to use my own magic to trick the "real one."
我想用自己的魔术来骗骗“真正的”
-Real one? -But my magic is all about deceiving people with fake tricks.
-真正的？ -我的魔术都是故弄玄虚的假把戏
However, I believe that in this world,
但我相信在这个世界上
there must exist real magic.
一定存在“真正的魔法”
My crime is sending messages
我犯下的罪行
to real wizards
就是对真正的魔法师
and superpowers!
以及超能力者所发出的信息
If the "real one" recognizes me as one of their own
如果“真正的” 认定我是他们的“同类”
and actively approaches me,
并主动来接近我 这就是一种证明
it is proof that in this world,
证明在这个世界上
there really is magic that has no tricks!
真的存在 没有玄机 不弄虚作假的魔法
What?
啥
Just because of this kind of juvenile reason,
你因为这种中二的理由
you caused a big stir throughout Japan?
就把整个日本闹得沸沸扬扬的吗
Everyone has a dreamy middle school student
每个人的心中
hidden in their heart, don't they?
都潜藏着一个会做梦的中学生啊
You know what?
你们知道吗
I look at the high school students that my imagination conjures up in my mind
我看着自己内心幻想出的中学生们 就会如此感叹
and can't help but sigh,
啊 这些孩子是多么地自由
"Ah, how free and pure these children are."
多么地纯真啊
As a responsible adult,
作为一个负责任的成年人
I must work to make their dreams come true.
就让我为他们实现梦想吧
Even if I become a sinner and
不管是成为罪人也好
cause chaos in the world, I will not hesitate!
把世界闹得鸡犬不宁也罢 我都在所不惜
I see.
原来如此
Arrest him.
给我把他抓起来
We can't tell
他最后说的话
which of his final words were true and which were made up.
哪些是真的 哪些是瞎编的 我们也搞不清楚
SHINJUKU POLICE STATION
(新宿警察局)
Although that guy has surpassed ordinary people in terms of techniques
虽然那家伙在技术和行动力方面 已经超乎常人
and action abilities, his most terrifying aspect is not limited to these.
但他最可怕的并不在于此
Not limited to these.
远远不止这些
-What is this? -This is a tool of civilization.
-这是什么 -这是文明的利器
I spent 2 000 yen on it at the
我在那边大街的二手工具店里
CORPSE GOD HAS OBTAINED A RADIO! second-hand tool store over there.
(尸神殿获得了收音机！) 花了两千日元买了这个
THE AMOUNT OF CASH HELD DECREASED FROM 20 000 YEN TO 18 000 YEN I bought this to gather intelligence.
(所持现金从两万日元减到一万八千日元) 我这是为了收集情报
With 20 000 yen, you could buy a cheap tablet instead.
两万日元的话 都可以买个便宜的平板电脑了
I CAN'T WEAR THIS DRESS ANYMORE
(我的连衣裙不能穿了)
Next up, we will report the following news.
接下来 播报下一则新闻
-The sound is very clear. -There was a police car fire incident this afternoon.
-有正常出声呢 -今天下午发生了警车起火事件
A suspect being escorted in the vehicle has been confirmed dead.
车内一名被押送的嫌犯已确认死亡
The suspect was arrested for suspected arson.
这名嫌犯 因涉嫌纵火而被逮捕
Gender is male, name unknown.
是位姓名不详的男性
-What? -Currently,
-什么 -目前
-the police are intensifying efforts to confirm the identity of the man. -Seriously?
-警方正在加紧确认该男子的身份 -喂喂 真的假的
He is the bastard who burned down the Shinoyama house back then.
他就是当时烧了四乃山家的混蛋啊
Next up is a brief news.
接下来是一则快讯
I wonder if everyone still remembers
雪车村天鸦这个名字
the name Tena Sorimura.
不知大家是否还有印象
25-YEAR VETERAN OF SHINJUKU POLICE STATION, FUMIYO YAMADA Oh no! Something big has happened.
(新宿警局任职25年 山田文代) 哎呀 大事不好了
Tsubaki-chan, come here!
小椿你们
Come over and watch this news.
快过来看电视
Who is Tsubaki-chan?
小椿是谁
Nickname of the Iwanome leader.
就是岩野目系长的名字
What happened?
发生什么事了
Look!
你们快看
"MAN WHO DISTURBED PUBLIC ORDER" ESCAPES FROM PRISON!! The news of Phantom Solitaire's escape
(“扰乱治安的男人”越狱!!) 电视上正在播放
is being broadcast on TV!
怪人雪天鸦越狱的新闻啊
-Hasn't the news already been blocked? -It should be blocked.
-我们不是已经限制报道了吗 -应该被限了才对啊
This man has kidnapped the Prime Minister and leaders of various political parties
这名男子绑架过 首相和各个政党的党首
but released them all within one day.
且在一天之内释放了他们
It was this self-directed and self-acted sexy man
迅速地让这一世纪大案落下帷幕的
who quickly brought an end to this century's major case.
正是这名自导自演的性感男子
Within the police force,
在警察内部
he has an exclusive nickname,
他还有一个专属称号
Phantom Solitaire.
叫做“怪人雪天鸦”
STRANGE, THIS NEWS IS TOO CASUAL He personally
(奇怪 这个快讯也太随意了吧) 就是他
IS IT AN ADVERTISEMENT DISGUISED AS NEWS? accomplished
(难道是包装成新闻的广告吗) 亲自完成了
-what people thought was impossible… -The person in the news is Phantom Solitaire?
-人们觉得不可能完成的事… -刚才广播里说的是怪人雪天鸦？
You know him?
你知道他吗
Although I have never met him in person, he is a celebrity.
虽然我没有当面见过他本人 但他可是个名人
At least in Japan, he is well-known.
至少在日本 他可是家喻户晓
BUT I HAVEN'T HEARD OF IT. Is that so?
(可是我没有听说过) 哦哦 是吗
After all, you have been the earthbound spirit here since five years ago.
毕竟你从五年前开始 就是这里的地缚灵了
Just like the Lemmings, he is also an urban legend in Shinjuku.
他和“旅鼠军团”一样 都是新宿的都市传说
However, the reason why that guy is called a legend
不过那家伙之所以被称为传说
is mainly because he has been exposed too much in the media.
主要是因为他在媒体上曝光太多了
Speaking of which, why did the news anchor change?
话说 为什么播新闻的人变了呢
Which TV station is this?!
喂 这是哪家电视台
VERIFY THE LEGEND OF TENA SORIMURA!! Are other TV stations showing this scene as well?
(验证 雪车村天鸦的传说!!) 其他电视台也是这个画面吗
For the world, this news can be
本则快讯对世界来说既是坏消息
seen as either bad or good.
也可以说是好消息吧
To all viewers in Japan,
日本的各位观众
as your beloved enemy,
作为你们亲爱的敌人
"THE MAN WHO DISTURBS PUBLIC ORDER" HAS ESCAPED!! I, Tena Sorimura, am making a comeback!
(“扰乱治安的男人”越狱!!) 我雪车村天鸦就此复出
No, my name now is Phantom Solitaire.
不 现在的我叫“怪人雪天鸦”
You will witness my return to the world!
你们将会见证我重出江湖的样子
Thank you to the police officers who named me.
感谢给我起名字的警察们
As a reward for using this name, I have prepared a grace period for you.
作为采用这个名字的奖励 我给你们准备了一段宽限期
My next performance will be in one week!
我的下次公演定于一周之后
Before that,
在那之前
please enjoy your life to the fullest, even if it may seem dull but beautiful!
请你们尽情享受 虽无趣但美好的人生吧
Adios? Ciao? Neither seems quite right.
Adios Ciao 好像都不太对啊
LET ME THINK! Hmm, a farewell greeting.
(容我想想！) 嗯 离别时的问候语
Let me think carefully before the next farewell comes.
在下次离别到来之前 让我好好想想
Good night!
晚安
WE'RE VERY SORRY. Uh, we're very sorry for
(非常抱歉) 呃 刚才发生了
-the visual confusion that just happened. -He hijacked the communication signal.
-画面混乱 实在非常抱歉 -他侵扰了电视的信号
He actually has this ability.
他居然还有这本事
No way. The Grocer must have sold him the broadcasting rights.
不可能 估计他是从“杂货殿” 那买了播放权
Isn't the Grocer still in detention?
杂货殿不是还在拘留中吗
It doesn't matter.
这不重要
For them, it doesn't matter where they live.
对他们来说 身居何处都无所谓
Thank you for your patronage.
多谢惠顾
That's right. This is the terrifying aspect of Phantom Solitaire.
没错 这就是怪人雪天鸦的可怕之处
He and Lisa Kuraki are of the same kind.
他和仓木丽莎是同一类人
They can naturally attract calamities that have nothing to do with each other
他们可以使那些 本来毫不相干的灾厄们
to gather around them.
自然而然地聚集到自己身边
Life is always unpredictable. I used to think,
人生总是世事难料啊
"There's no magic in this world," and fell into despair, locked myself in a cell.
我因为“这世界没有魔法” 而陷入绝望 将自己囚于牢狱
But then new possibilities emerged.
但这时却出现了新的可能性
Don't you think so?
你不这么认为吗
The Firestarter.
“赴火之虫”
But I really didn't expect that you would respond to my call.
不过我还真没想到 你竟会回应我的呼唤
This phone ringtone is really relaxing.
这手机铃声真令人放松
Although I have lost face, at least I am a magician.
虽说我已颜面扫地 但我好歹也是个魔术师
I like this music.
我喜欢这个曲子
However, although it is famous,
然而 虽然它很有名
many people do not know its title.
但意外地却有许多人不知道它的曲名
UNKNOWN NUMBER CALLING
(未知号码来电)
Sorry, could you wait for me a moment?
抱歉 你能稍等我片刻吗
Perhaps it's a call from the Grocer to confirm the delivery with me.
应该是杂货殿打来 向我确认收货的电话吧
Olive Necklace.
“橄榄项链”
This is…a well-known piece
这是…波尔玛丽亚…演奏的
played by…Paul Mauriat.
知名…曲子
How did you find out this phone number?
呃 你是怎么知道这个手机号码的
Let's put that aside for now.
这事暂且不论
Is it really necessary to use the phone when we're so close?
但说实话 这么近距离的交谈 有必要用电话吗
Aren't you just wasting broadband and call charges?
你这不是在浪费宽频和电话费吗
I really don't want to…
我还真不想…
be lectured by…someone who… wastes their life like you.
被浪费生命的你…这样说教
How did you…notice my existence?
你是怎么…察觉到我的存在的
That's because…
那是因为…
Oh my, are you planning to burn me too?
哎呀 你这是打算把我也烧了吗
Just like how that short and pitiful
就像烧了那个矮小可悲的
imposter of yours was burned.
假冒你的人一样
Is he a very skilled criminal?
他是个很厉害的罪犯吗
The Tena Sorimura.
雪车村天鸦
I heard about his name too.
我也听过他的名字
Polka, are there no people like this in your hometown's world?
波尔卡 你家乡的世界里 没有这样的人吗
A well-known national enemy-like guy.
人尽皆知的国家公敌般的家伙
STICKY WITCH "RADIAL" SEA CLAN MAYOR "DELGA", VAMPIRE NOBLE "SILKA", TRANSPARENT RAMPAGING ANDROID "MEDIEN", ALCHEMIST OF THE FLOATING WORKSHOP "PANI"
(粘着魔女“拉迪亚尔” 海族市长“德尔加” 吸血鬼贵族“西尔卡” 透明暴走人造人“梅迪恩” ）
If it's something even someone like me who lives
（浮游工坊的炼金学士“帕尼”) 如果说是就连深居煤矿的我
I'M KIND OF INTERESTED IN SILKA. deep in the coal mine has heard of,
(我对西尔卡有点兴趣呢) 都听过的话
such as the "King-Killer" who killed the kingdom of Nyanild,
比如说 杀死努安伊尔德王国的 “先帝刺客”
the poison dragon, Pirawizzo.
“废毒龙 皮拉维佐”
I've heard that it fought to a draw with the man known as the Calamity Crusher
听说它与被称作“灾厄歼灭者”的 那个男人打成平手
before fleeing the kingdom.
然后逃离了王国
It was only after hearing this news that
我就是在听说这个消息后
I began to entertain thoughts that perhaps this Calamity Crusher could also kill me.
才萌生了“灾厄歼灭者” 也许能够杀死我这样的想法
-Pour son dragon? -It's a kind of dragon.
-飞独隆？ -就是一种龙
It is a creature that is almost the size of a car in volume,
它是一种体积差不多有一辆车那么大
but can easily kill the giant Dragon Emperor insect.
但却可以轻易杀死巨大龙帝虫的怪物
As for the Dragon Emperor insect mentioned earlier,
至于刚才说到的龙帝虫
THIS, PIRAWIZZO I later made use of it.
(这个　皮拉维佐) 后来为我所用了
Although I am used to seeing strange things,
虽说我已经见怪不怪了
your world still has dragons.
不过你的世界还有龙啊
Doesn't this world have them?
这个世界难道没有吗
ILLUSTRATED GUIDE TO FANTASY ANIMALS' ECOLOGY I have seen many stories that mention dragons,
(《幻想动物生态图鉴》) 我看到很多故事里都有提到龙
and their shapes are also similar. I thought there might be some here too.
而且体型也很相似 我还以为这里也有呢
HMM, WORTH PONDERING.
(嗯 值得深思)
THE CREATURES IN THE WORLD OF POLKA AND THE IMAGINARY CREATURES IN OUR WORLD.
(波尔卡所在世界的生物 和我们这的幻想生物)
MAYBE WE SHOULD TAKE SOME TIME TO MAKE A THOROUGH COMPARISON.
(我们也许应该找时间 彻底比较一下呢)
Yes, maybe there are other commonalities to be discovered.
是啊 我们也许还能发现 其他的共同点
And it seems that there are also spirits of wind and fire.
何况这世界似乎还有风与火的精灵
SPIRIT ELEMENTAL, FIRE DRAGON, SERAPHINE
(元素精灵) (火龙 西尔芙)
You're really amazing, just like a fire spirit.
真厉害啊 你就像火精灵一样
Geez.
真是的
Can't you just listen to me for a moment?
你就不能稍微听我说会话嘛
What do you… want to say?
你要…说什么
What to say?
说什么
Do I even need to answer that question?
这还用问
Of course is nonsense.
当然是废话
Earlier, I questioned you about why you would waste phone charges,
刚才我质问你 为什么要浪费电话费
but that doesn't mean I'm denying you!
并不是否定你的意思
As a matter of fact,
因为我这个人
I am someone who enjoys the concept of "waste" the most!
最喜欢“浪费”这个概念了
The secret to enjoying life lies in whether or not we can enjoy these wastes—
因为享受人生的秘诀 就在于是否能享受这些浪费
wasting time, effort,
浪费时间 浪费努力
and money.
浪费金钱
And if we eliminate waste altogether,
而杜绝浪费的最终结果
all that will be left in our lives is breathing, eating, and sleeping.
就是我们的人生 只剩下呼吸 吃饭和睡觉了
And in this way, we will be no different from machines.
而这样的我们将和机器毫无差别
Because if just being alive is enough,
因为只要活着就够了的话
then aren't human emotions
人的情感本身
also a kind of waste?
不也是一种浪费吗
This is…your…sophistry.
这是…你的…诡辩
I am…unable to…communicate with you.
我和你…无法…交流
People will experience happiness and pain
人们只要活在这世上
as long as…they live…in this world.
就会感到…快乐…和…痛苦
Emotion is…not a defect…
情感…不是…缺陷
it's a part…of life…
它是…生命系统的… 一部分
You're right! Anyway, let me praise you first.
你说的对 总之我先称赞你一下
I don't have the answer myself
我自己既没有答案
and I've never thought about the meaning of life!
也从没有考虑过人生的意义
Is it sophistry? Not really!
诡辩 非也
I'm just playing a word game.
我只是在玩文字游戏
But you're correct about being unable to communicate!
但无法交流这点你说的是正确的
I just wanted to say some serious words
我只不过是想先说一些煞有介事的话
and then try to get away with it smoothly.
然后顺势蒙混过关而已
I never expected you would see through me!
没想到居然被你看穿了
Isn't it incredible?
不可思议吧
Do you feel no weight at all?
你是不是一点也感觉不到重量
But this is just a magic trick,
不过这也只是魔术
a deceptive illusion,
是弄虚作假的把戏
like your fire.
和你的火一样
Your power is not magic or superpower. This makes me feel extremely regretful.
你的那个力量并不是魔法或超能力 这让我感觉遗憾至极
I am not interested in… fairy tales…
我对…童话…不感兴趣
But what if one day fairy tales became reality?
但如果有一天童话故事变成现实了呢
In this world that you consider abnormal,
在这个你认为“不正常的世界”里
what if there really is an alien intrusion?
要是真的有异物混进来了呢
The "thing" that appeared in Shinjuku,
在新宿出现的“那个东西”
do you consider it a "defect" that should be eliminated?
对你来说是否属于 应该消除的“缺陷”
Don't you want to personally find out?
你难道不想亲自弄清楚吗
If my judgment is that they are "pests that should be burned,"
如果我的判断是“应该烧毁的害虫”
what do you plan to do?
你准备怎么办
Let's think about that when the time comes.
那时候的事 就到那时候再想吧
You are too obsessed… with supernatural phenomena.
你过于沉迷…超自然现象了吧
Didn't I tell you before?
我不是说了吗
I love waste the most.
我最喜欢“浪费”这件事了
However, when it comes to dragons,
不过该怎么说呢 龙嘛
their name alone makes them a national enemy due to their destructive power.
从破坏力上来说 单看名字 确实是“国家公敌”级别的了
But compared to these creatures,
不过和这些生物比起来
our criminals here don't seem that terrifying.
我们这里的罪犯们似乎没那么可怕吧
However, it's not entirely accurate to say that.
也不能完全这么说
In this world, magic doesn't exist,
这个世界不存在魔法
so the premises of the two are completely different.
所以两者的前提完全不一样
Moreover, the Lemmings
而且 那个“旅鼠军团”
is also a very dangerous presence in my hometown.
在我的家乡也属于非常危险的存在
Could it be the Lemmings?
不会是旅鼠军团吧
STUFFED
(塞满)
Good evening.
晚上好
How are you, Polka?
你还好吗 波尔卡
Huh?
咦
(Episode 8: The Assassin)
(第8集 The Assassin -暗杀者-)